Quick note, if you haven't seen it yet,
we did send a buy alert to course
members, but for now, let's talk about
Elon.
>> Well, I have to say this level of a shy
stirring was not on my bingo board for
Tesla and SpaceX. Obviously, we have
been talking about the potential for a
merger between the companies for a long
time. And we just found out that
apparently all of the stock comp
service-based milestones that Elon
promised can basically get waived in the
event of a merger.
Literally, the approved milestones that
shareholders voted on at Tesla, which
say that, "Hey, we want Tesla to hit a
certain market cap and service-based
milestones,
including
10 million active FSD subscriptions.
We're currently at 1.48 million as of
the second quarter. 55% of those people
bought up front, so only around 700-ish
thousand are actually paying on a
monthly basis, right? We're supposed to
get to 10 million. We're a fraction of
the way there, about 14% of the way
there. Looking for 20 million cumulative
vehicle deliveries, we're almost halfway
there at about 9.7 million. Looking for
1 million robotaxis in operation,
we're at 20 unsupervised.
It's trying to get there. It's taking a
little longer than expected, but we're
working on it. 1 million Optimus robots
delivered, obviously this is zero for,
you know, commercial purposes.
Uh and then of course we have the
market-cap-based milestones, which of
those will survive. But every single one
of those milestones, Optimus, robotaxi,
cumulative vehicle deliveries, FSD
subscriptions, all of those vanish as a
requirement for Elon to get paid out
stock comp in the event of a merger
between Tesla and SpaceX. And that is
due to this particular clause on
uh
it's actually on page four over here of
the way I printed the stock comp plan.
Some people have printed this to
indicate it's on page 16. For me, it's
on page five. I don't know. But, take a
look at this.
This is the document here. So, you can
see this is the 2025 CEO Performance
Award Agreement for Tesla. 2025 CEO
Performance Restricted
Stock Agreement. You can see here
September 3rd, 2025. Tesla agrees to
blah blah blah. This is what
shareholders voted on, right? If we go
down, these are the market caps, by the
way. You can see right here.
And they come with operational
milestones in addition to market cap,
right? So, the first tranche, $2
trillion
market cap for Tesla. That's on a 30-day
like weighted moving average going back.
So, it's not just like it's there for a
moment. It has to be there for a good
month, approximately.
Uh but, you would then have to achieve
one of the 12 operational milestones. I
just gave us some of them. Uh you can
see here, this is what I listed. 20
million vehicle deliveries, the 10
million FSD subscriptions, the 1 million
bot deliveries, the 1 million robotaxis,
uh or
uh any of the following, which are
basically increments of billions of
dollars of adjusted EBITDA.
Okay. So, in other words, uh without any
actual earnings requirements,
you could basically get all the way to
operational milestone number four right
here solely based on market cap without
hitting any kind of earnings, right?
But, in the event of a merger,
all of this right here is stricken. None
of these matter. There's only one thing
that matters. The only thing that
matters for how much Elon gets paid
is this section right here. Let's make
it a box. That's it. Market cap. Which
given that SpaceX
is controlled by Elon
and SpaceX would be presumed to buy
Tesla,
Elon can basically decide uh which
tranche
>> [laughter]
>> do you want to get paid at
on, right? Now, of course, that is
assuming that uh the market cap for
Tesla rises and in order to actually
afford this at SpaceX without being
extremely diluted,
uh you would assume that SpaceX would
have to really grow in market cap
substantially, which you know, it can
do. But, where the clause is buried is
right here on page five.
And again, the print formatting can kind
of move this around a little bit. Right
here.
Notwithstanding section one, two, and
three above. So, one, two, three uh
above just for uh reference, that's
going to be the determining the
achievement of operational milestones.
So, basically, how they determine
determining the achievement of market
cap. This is where the part of the
30-day market cap is, blah blah blah.
Uh and then of course, one are the
actual milestones. So, so just
basically, ignoring all of that for a
moment, in the event of a change in
control,
all of the operational milestones above
shall literally be disregarded
and the market capitalization
shall basically be what was the price
immediately before
the acquisition or the change in
control.
So, in other words,
hey, if Tesla
uh gets some kind of really large
premium offer, right? This is what the
Wall Street Journal is talking about
today, which you know,
some people don't like the Wall Street
Journal, but the Wall Street Journal is
basically making this argument that,
"Hey, you know, Elon could do a $2
trillion acquisition, which would be
about $506 per share over at Tesla." And
they're calling this article, "See how a
Tesla SpaceX merger gives Musk a
shortcut to his trillion-dollar payday."
And they go through these various
different scenarios of prices and all
this. I think this is a little
overcomplicated the way they wrote this
article.
But basically, if there's a a $2
trillion
acquisition price for Tesla, which would
be a 53% premium to today's pricing,
then Elon would be able to unlock his
first tranche immediately
regardless
of whether or not a single one of those
operational milestones has actually been
achieved.
So,
if
Elon does acquire Tesla for $2 trillion
at about $506 per share, Elon would be
granted about $17.9 billion
before tax in stock options.
Now, $17.9 billion isn't really the play
here. $17.9 billion for somebody who's a
trillionaire isn't a big deal. That's
like a $20 bill when you have $1,000 in
your bank account.
I mean, you still want the 20, but it's
a rounding error compared to the about
12.7% stake you have in Tesla.
See, at $2 trillion,
a 12.7%
stake at $2 trillion works out to about
$250
billion. So, in other words, the higher
the share price is for Tesla at
acquisition by SpaceX, the more money
Elon makes from Stock Comp
without operational milestones,
and the more money that his actual Tesla
ownership is worth which then just
translates into more SpaceX stock.
So,
what does this mean? In my opinion, this
is again brilliant optionality by Elon
though it's kind of evil because it's
not what shareholders really intended to
vote on. Uh but I don't think people
would be pissed if their shares get sold
for $500 or some crazy premium, right?
So, it's sort of like it's a nuanced
like
ah good one Elon. We see what you did
there but we still like the fact that
we're getting paid a premium for the
shares. The people who potentially get
screwed are really the other SpaceX
shareholders which which which I am
also.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh so,
because if you pay
too much of a premium for Tesla and it
hasn't earned it because of those
operational milestones,
then this really fat premium at Tesla to
allow Elon to move these highly
appreciated shares based on their own
purchase price to allow him to move
those into SpaceX ownership to increase
his SpaceX ownership at a high Tesla
valuation is good for him but not good
for SpaceX shareholders.
So, that's the built-in risk factor
here. But this is I have to say is
brilliant but it's also shystery. This
is not, in my opinion, what people
thought they were voting for when they
voted for the stock comp plan. I think
people are like, "Hey man, like if Tesla
can go up to this share price for a
period of, you know, 30 days or
whatever, hit those milestones and we
can hit some of these operational
milestones, fine. Let the guy be paid.
Let the man make his money. If he makes
everybody else money and he actually
grows the business to where it's a good
business that's going into SpaceX which
is then good and accretive to Tesla
share well, maybe not accretive but it's
it's beneficial to SpaceX shareholders.
Great. Let the man make his money.
But, this kind of perverses the
incentives a little bit. Really, what
you're doing is you're saying, "Hey,
if SpaceX decides to pay a massive
premium for Tesla, even though it's not
hitting any of its massive
you know, it's operational milestones,
oh, well,
we're still going to do the merger and
we're still going to take our stock hump
and our inflated ownership of SpaceX."
Crazy. That's all I have to say about
it. And if any of that makes you
nervous, don't worry, come join us over
at meetkevin.com. We'd love to have you.
We just sent out another buy alert. Talk
to you soon. Goodbye and good luck.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> Well, we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done
[music] so much. People love you. People
look up to you.
>> Kevin Paffrath there, financial analyst
and YouTuber, Meet Kevin. Always great
to get your [music] take.